You better watch out!
How the Grinch Stole Christmas is a family, comedy,
fantasy film directed by Ron Howard.
The Grinch decides to rob Whoville of Christmas - but a dash of kindness from
little Cindy Lou Who and her family may be enough to melt his heart...
Grinch, played by Jim Carrey.
Cindy Lou Who, played by Taylor Momsen.
Mayor Augustus Maywho, played by Jeffrey Tambor.
Martha May Whovier, played by Christine Baranski.
Lou Lou Who, played by Bill Irwin.
Betty Lou Who, played by Molly Shannon.
Seuss' How the Grinch Stole Christmas is a 2000 American Christmas comedy film
directed by Ron Howard and written by Jeffrey Price and Peter S.
Seaman, based on the 1957 children's book by Dr.
It was the first Seuss book to be adapted into a live-action feature film, and the
second adaptation of the book following the 1966 animated TV special.
Narrated by Anthony Hopkins, the film stars Jim Carrey as the Grinch, with Jeffrey Tambor,
Christine Baranski, Bill Irwin, Taylor Momsen and Molly Shannon in supporting roles.
The story revolves around a misanthropic green creature living on Mount Crumpit, who despises Christmas
and the joyful residents of Whoville and sets out to sabotage their holiday celebration.
How the Grinch Stole Christmas premiered in Los Angeles on November 8, 2000, and was
released in the United States on November 17 by Universal Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics, and was a box-office success, grossing $351 million on a budget of $123 million, becoming the highest-grossing film of 2000
domestically, the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2000 worldwide, and the fourth-highest-grossing holiday film of all time behind Home Alone 2: Lost in New York (1992).
At the 73rd Academy Awards, the film won Best Makeup and Hairstyling, in addition to
earning nominations for Best Production Design and Best Costume Design.
Carrey's performance earned him a nomination for the Golden Globe Award
for Best Actor in a Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
The film explores themes of new love, based on novel or
book, holiday, christmas party, village.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.